Brown and Blue Yearbook UP023
Digital Collections and Archives, Tufts University
Brown and Blue Yearbook
1888 -- 1899
1878 -- 1904
Digital Collections and Archives, Tufts University
Zeta Psi fraternity, Kappa Chapter
UP023
0.25 Linear Feet
9 Volumes
Arrangement
This collection is organized into one series.
Scope and Contents
This collection consists of several yearbook-like publications under related titles. Between 1864 and 1877, the Zeta Psi fraternity and the "Secret Society" produced a publication called the "Tuftonian." In 1878, the name "Tuftonian" was taken by the literary magazine originally called the "Tufts Collegian." Zeta Psi continued to produce a yearbook publication and called it the "Brown and Blue" in reference to the College colors. By 1888 the "Brown and Blue" had developed into a modern yearbook and was published by the Junior Class. The "Brown and Blue" was published intermittently into the early part of the twentieth century. Reviving the yearbook at Tufts, a Tufts yearbook was published in 1916. In 1917, the first "Jumbo" yearbook was published, this time by the senior class.
There is no editorial relationship between the "Tuftonian" in this collection and the later literary magazine of the same name.
Biographical / Historical
The Kappa Chapter at Tufts was the eleventh Zeta Psi group to be granted a charter. In 1855, Robert M. Morse, Jr. and J.L. Flagg, members of the Rho Chapter at Harvard, founded the Kappa Chapter and entrusted Benjamin A. Hathaway of tufts with the task of selecting the charter members. He soon chose six other men who were initiated a few weeks later at Harvard, thus making the Kappa the oldest fraternity chapter at Tufts.
A yearbook-like publication called the "Tuftonian" was produced by the Zeta Psi Fraternity and the "Secret Society" between 1864 and 1877. In 1878, the name "Tuftonian" was taken by the literary magazine originally called the "Tufts Collegian." Zeta Psi continued to produce a yearbook publication and called it the "Brown and Blue" in reference to the College colors. By 1888 the Brown and Blue had developed into a modern yearbook and was published by the junior class. The "Brown and Blue" was published intermittently into the early part of the twentieth century. In 1917, the first "Jumbo" yearbook was published, this time by the senior class, reviving the yearbook at Tufts.
There is no editorial relationship between the "Tuftonian" in this series and the later literary magazine of the same name.
- Brown and Blue, 1878 -- 1904; 1888 -- 1899; UP023.001; 0.25 Linear Feet; 9 Volumes
  Scope and Contents
  This series contains a yearbook-like publication called the "Tuftonian" was produced by the Zeta Psi Fraternity and the "Secret Society" between 1864 and 1877. In 1878, the name "Tuftonian" was taken by the literary magazine originally called the "Tufts Collegian." Zeta Psi continued to produce a yearbook publication and called it the "Brown and Blue" in reference to the College colors. By 1888 the Brown and Blue had developed into a modern yearbook and was published by the junior class. The "Brown and Blue" was published intermittently into the early part of the twentieth century. In 1917, the first "Jumbo" yearbook was published, this time by the senior class, reviving the yearbook at Tufts.
  Arrangement
  This series is arranged chronologically.
  Conditions Governing Access
  Open for research.
  - Brown and Blue, 1878; UP023.001.001.00001; 1 Digital Object(s); 8.6 Megabytes (Box 1)
  - Brown and Blue, 1879; UP023.001.001.00002; 9.43 Megabytes; 1 Digital Object(s) (Box 1)
  - Brown and Blue, 1888; UP023.001.001.00003; 1 Digital Object(s); 11.3 Megabytes (Box 1)
  - Brown and Blue, 1889; UP023.001.002.001; 1 Digital Object(s); 27.5 Megabytes (Box Volume 2)
  - Brown and Blue, 1890; UP023.001.003.001; 1 Digital Object(s); 21.1 Megabytes (Box Volume 3)
  - Brown and Blue, 1891; UP023.001.004.001; 1 Digital Object(s); 15.6 Megabytes (Box Volume 4)
  - Brown and Blue, 1892; UP023.001.005.001; 1 Digital Object(s); 55.1 Megabytes (Box Volume 5)
  - Brown and Blue, 1893; UP023.001.006.001; 1 Digital Object(s); 16 Megabytes (Box Volume 6)
  - Brown and Blue, 1894; UP023.001.007.001; 1 Digital Object(s); 82.7 Megabytes (Box Volume 7)
  - Brown and Blue, 1896; UP023.001.008.001; 1 Digital Object(s); 76.9 Megabytes (Box Volume 8)
  - Brown and Blue, 1899; UP023.001.009.001; 1 Digital Object(s); 24.2 Megabytes (Box Volume 9)
  - Brown and Blue, 1904; UP023.001.010.001; 1 Digital Object(s); 9.5 Megabytes (Box Volume 10)